Hector Obanana

Junior Software Developer

Peterborough

07306 891589 | hectorjana.o@gmail.com

github.com/hjaox | hjaox.github.io/ | linkedin.com/in/hector-obañana/

Personal Profile

I am making an exciting career change into Software Development making use of my problem-solving and analytical/logical thinking skills I have developed in my former career in the Electrical Engineering field. Currently taking 13-Week Boot Camp in Software engineering under a multi-award-winning tech education Northcoders to advance my knowledge in coding so I may gain the tools to build projects with increasing complexity, and as well experience working in a team environment to help me kick-start my career in the Software Development Industry.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript

Front-End: HTML, CSS, React, React-Native Back-End: PostgreSQL, node-Postgres

Testing: Test-Diven Development (TDD), Jest, Supertest

Hosting: Render, Netlify, ElephantSQL Other: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

Projects

NC News Front-end Project

The purpose of this repository is to serve as a front-end architecture for the back-end API that I have built (See NC News Back-end Project).

Technologies used: React, JavaScript, React-Bootstrap, CSS, Axios

NC News Back-end Project

The purpose of this repository is to learn how to build an API for accessing application data programmatically. The intention is to mimic the building of a real-world backend services which should provide information to the front-end architecture.

Technologies used: JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Express, Jest, Supertest, node-Postgres

Experience

Trainee Software Developer, Northcoders – Software Engineering Bootcamp (Jul 2023 - Ongoing)

During the 13-week Bootcamp where I learned the fundamentals of Full-Stack Development, I acquired the fundamentals of JavaScript which helped me in creating a back-end service to provide data for a front-end architecture that I have built. All throughout the process, I aimed to build clean testable codes by following Test Driven Development process with agile methodologies while both working solo or working with colleagues through pair-programming or in group projects.

Plant Operator, SUEZ Water Technologies and Solutions UK L P (Feb 2022 – Sept 2022)

- Quality Control of different types of water treatment equipment
- Troubleshooting electrical and control systems in fleet equipment

Admin Staff, Clippers Logistics (PE3) under Staffing Match Agency (Aug 2021 – Feb 2022)

Cooperating with several departments to allocate orders for E-commerce and Retail Customers

Technician, Bake n'Cake in Dubai (Nov 2019 – Mar 2020)

Maintaining equipment operation and other electrical systems in of the building

Building Engineer, First Oceanic Property Management Inc. In Philippines (March 2017 - May 2018)

- Managing the operation of the building (Three Techno Place Building) both staff (Security, Housekeeping and Maintenance Crew) and equipment system (Mechanical, Electrical, etc.)
- Performing basic in-house Preventive Maintenance daily and monthly of building systems

Site Engineer, Golden Sky Trading and Engineering Services WLL in Qatar (July 2015 – March 2016)

- Design and help fabricate Motor Control Panels/Protection (MCP)
- Supervision of Manpower on other tasks

Education

Central Philippine University: Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

UK Comparison Framework Levels: RFQ Level 5 / SCQF Level 8 / CQFW Level 5

Comparable UK Qualifications: Foundation Degree / BTEC Level 5 / SQA Higher / National Diploma (HND) (SCQF Level 8)